Guide to the Glen E. Myers Stanford Class Notes
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Glen E. Meyers Stanford class notes
1956-1962
SC0675
Myers, Glen E., 1934-
2.75 Linear feet
This collection contains syllabi, course handouts, problem sets, exams, and Myers' notes from engineering, math, and physics classes he took at Stanford, 1956-59; for the elementary engineering thermodynamics classes for which he was a teaching assistant, 1958-59; and for the class on elementary engineering thermodynamics that he taught at Stanford during the summer of 1962. Professors of these classes include Karl Klotter, Wilhelm Flugge, Irmgard Flugge-Lotz, G. E. Pake, G. E. Latta, Felix Bloch, David F. Tuttle, and P. R. Garabedian.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Glen E. Myers, 2003.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Glen E. Myers studied mechanical engineering at Stanford, earning his M.S. in 1957 and his Ph.D. in 1962. He joined the faculty at the University of Wisconsin-Madison in 1962 and was appointed Professor Emeritus there in 2001.
Description of the Collection
This collection contains syllabi, course handouts, problem sets, exams, and Myers' notes from engineering, math, and physics classes he took at Stanford, 1956-59; for the elementary engineering thermodynamics classes for which he was a teaching assistant, 1958-59; and for the class on elementary engineering thermodynamics that he taught at Stanford during the summer of 1962. Professors of these classes include Karl Klotter, Wilhelm Flugge, Irmgard Flugge-Lotz, G. E. Pake, G. E. Latta, Felix Bloch, David F. Tuttle, and P. R. Garabedian.
Access Terms
Bloch, Felix, 1905-; Flugge, Wilhelm, 1904-; Flugge-Lotz, Irmgard.; Garabedian, P. R.; Klotter, Karl.; Latta, G. E.; Myers, Glen E., 1934-; Myers, Glen E., 1934-; Pake, G. E. (George Edward).; Tuttle, David F.; Engineering--Curricula.; Mathematics--Study and teaching.; Physics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Academic Year 1956-57
    - ME 231a – A. L. London – Heat Transmission (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ME 238a – R. H. Eustis – Mechanics and Thermodynamics of Fluid Flow (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ME 238b – S. J. Kline - Mechanics and Thermodynamics of Fluid Flow (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ME 233a – S. J. Kline – Advanced Thermodynamics (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - ME 233a – R. H. Eustis – Advanced Thermodynamics (audit, Autumn 1957) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - EM 221 – K. Klotter – Advanced Dynamics (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - EM 222 – K. Klotter – Advanced Dynamics (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - EM 223 – K. Klotter – Advanced Dynamics (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - EM 250 – J. N. Goodier – Mathematical Methods in Engineering Mechanics (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - EM 251 – K. Klotter – Mathematical Methods in Engineering Mechanics (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - EM 252 – W. Flügge – Numerical Methods in Engineering Mechanics (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - ME 231b – W. M. Kays – Heat Transmission (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Math 113 – G. A. Hufford – Vector Analysis (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - ME 232 – A. L. London – Experimental Problems in Heat Transmission (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - EM 244 – I. Flügge-Lotz – Mathematical Hydro- and Aerodynamics (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - AE 255 – D. Bershader – Aerodynamic Physical Measurements (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Academic Year 1957-58
    - Math 106 – G. E. Latta – Complex Variables (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - EE 235 – G. Wade – Network Analysis (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Physics 111 – G. E. Pake – Introduction to Theoretical Physics (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Physics 113 – G. E. Pake – Introduction to Theoretical Physics (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Physics 115 – G. E. Pake – Introduction to Theoretical Physics (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Physics 173 – F. Bloch - Thermodynamics (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Physics 175 – F. Bloch – Kinetic Theory of Gases (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Math 131 – G. E. Latta – Partial Differential Equations I (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Math 132 – G. E. Latta – Partial Differential Equations II (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - EM 231 – D. F. Tuttle – Non-Linear Oscillations (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - EM 232 – D. F. Tuttle – Non-Linear Oscillations (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - ME 237a – A. L. London – Thermodynamics of Propulsion Systems (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Math 201 – P. W. Berg – Calculus of Variations (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - ? – ? – ? (audit) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Academic Year 1958-59
    - Math 209a – P. R. Garabedian – Advanced Partial Differential Equations (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Math 209b – P. R. Garabedian – Advanced Partial Differential Equations (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Math 209c – P. R. Garabedian – Advanced Partial Differential Equations (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - ME 271a – G. Leppert – Nuclear Reactor Theory (audit) (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - ME 131 – Various – Elementary Engineering Thermodynamics [Myers was the TA for these classes] (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Math 223 – M. M. Schiffer – Integral Equations (audit) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Summer 1962
    - ME 131 – G. E. Myers – Elementary Engineering Thermodynamics (Box 6, Folder 23)